Guide to the Norma Bicknell and Robert Stuart Mansfield Papers 1929-1970
Special Collections and University Archives, University of Oregon Libraries
Norma Bicknell and Robert Stuart Mansfield papers
1929-1970
Ax 765
Special Collections and University Archives, University of Oregon Libraries 1299 University of Oregon Eugene, Oregon, 97403-1299 (541) 346-3068 spcarref@uoregon.edu
5.5 linear feet 5 containers
Norma Bicknell (1906-1965) and Robert Mansfield (1906- ) met and married in 1925 while students at the University of Michigan; as undergraduates, both studied creative writing. The collection includes many manuscripts, correspondence and miscellaneous material.
5 containers
Mansfield, Norma Bicknell; Mansfield, Robert Stuart, 1906-
Box 1-5
Biographical/Historical note
Norma Bicknell and Robert Mansfield met and married in 1925 while students at the University of Michigan; as undergraduates, both studied creative writing under the direction of Donal Hamilton Haines. Of the two writers, Robert Mansfield was first to have material accepted for publication. 1927 saw the beginning of a long series of publications over a period of ten years in young peoples' magazines such as the Haversack, The Torchbearer, the Class Mate, and the High Road. By 1930, the same magazines, along with The American Girl, were publishing Norma Mansfield's short stories on a regular basis as well.
While Robert Mansfield continued at the University of Michigan, earning a Master's Degree in Journalism, Norma Mansfield began work on the first of four juvenile books, which were to be published in the 1930s. Each of the books first appeared in serial form in Tthe American Gir l under the titles, Keeper of the Wolves, Boss of the Ragged O, McCallister Patrol, and The Girl from Frozen Bend. While waiting for a teaching position to open up for Mr. Mansfield, the couple spent what they called their "bohemian years" traveling, camping, and selling enough magazine fiction to provide a small income. During the depression, Robert Mansfield held a position as instructor in the University of Washington School of Journalism. It was at this time that he began writing and selling adult fiction to the Saturday Evening Post, Collier's and Liberty. While the early years of his career was divided between the interests of writing and teaching, by the late 1930s, Mr. Mansfield devoted himself almost entirely to teaching. For this reason, other then seven short stories published in magazines in the 1940s and one co-authored book from 1970, examples in the collection of his writing date primarily form the 1920s and 1930s. In the 25 years that Robert Mansfield taught at the University of Washington, he became full professor and, finally, acting director of the School of Journalism. As a teacher, he was particularly noted for his short story seminars. In 1959, he left the teaching profession to become assistant public relations manager of the Boeing Airplane Company of Seattle.
Norma Mansfield's success as a writer of short stories for magazine publications began after 1937, when she turned from juvenile to adult fiction. It was in this year that she turned from juvenile to adult fiction and began her twenty-year-long working relationship with the New York literary agent, Carl Brandt. Under Brandt's guidance, Norma Mansfield's fiction was submitted to and accepted by magazines such as The Saturday Evening Post, Liberty, Collier's, Cosmopolitan, American, McCall's, and Woman's Home Companion. The Saturday Evening Post alone published more than 27 of her short stories.
The Norma Bicknell and Robert Stuart Mansfield Papers include many manuscripts, correspondence and miscellaneous material. The majority of the manuscripts in the collection are of the standard 17 to 21 page magazine fiction length. A common background for many of the stories seems to have been determined by Norma Mansfield's childhood in rural Eastern Washington, since many of the stories deal with ranching and with outdoor life in the West. The Mansfields collaborated only occasionally on stories, examples included in the collection are "Fool's Mate" and "Printer's Ink". Also, the collection includes over 450 letters written by Carl Brandt to both of the Mansfields during the years from 1937 to 1957; in addition, business details relating to the sale of material are well documented in agency correspondence.
Collection is organized into the following series:
Series: Correspondence (Norma Bicknell) (1929-1960)
Series: Manuscripts (Norma Bicknell)
Series: Publications (Norma Bicknell)
Series: Correspondence (Robert Mansfield)
Series: Manuscripts (Robert Mansfield)
Series: Publications (Robert Mansfield)
Collection is open to the public.
Collection must be used in Special Collections University Archives Reading Room.
Gift of Norma Bicknell and Robert Stuart Mansfield in 1974.
Brandt, Carl G.; Mansfield, Norma Bicknell--Correspondence; Mansfield, Norma Bicknell; Mansfield, Robert Stuart, 1906---Correspondence; Mansfield, Robert Stuart, 1906-
West (U.S.)--In literature
Authors, American--20th century; Literary agents--Correspondence; Publishers and publishing--Correspondence; Short stories, American--Authorship; Western stories--Authorship; Women authors, American--20th century; Young adult literature, American--Authorship
Children and Youth; Journalism; Literature; Publishers and Publishing; Women
Manuscripts for publication
- Correspondence (Norma Bicknell), 1929-1960
  - Albert, Paul, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 1-11)
  - Barach, Frederica, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 1-11)
  - Bishop, Maitland C., 1941 (Box 1, Folder 1-11)
  - Borgstedt, Douglas, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 1-11)
  - Brandt, Erdmann, 1941-1958 (Box 1, Folder 1-11)
  - Brandt Brandt (Box 1, Folder 1-11)
  - Brandt, Carl, 1937-1957 (Box 1, Folder 1-11)
  - Bridge, Margaret, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 1-11)
  - Brown, Kelly, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 1-11)
  - Brownlee, Lucy Ann (Box 1, Folder 1-11)
  - Burack, A. S., 1950 (Box 1, Folder 1-11)
  - Campbell, Lawson Jr., 1949 (Box 1, Folder 1-11)
  - Caudill, Rebecca, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 1-11)
  - Chambrun, Jacques, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 1-11)
  - Conger, Lucille B., 1940 (Box 1, Folder 1-11)
  - Craig, Archibald, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 1-11)
  - Delonis, Estelle, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 1-11)
  - Downey, Fairfax, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 1-11)
  - Felton, Ray, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 1-11)
  - Ferguson, Rowena, 1929-1935 (Box 1, Folder 1-11)
  - Ferris, Helen, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 1-11)
  - Finnin, Betty, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 1-11)
  - Fish, Byron, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 1-11)
  - Gallico, Paul, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 1-11)
  - Gillespia, A. Lincoln Jr. (Box 1, Folder 1-11)
  - Gilman, Elizabeth L. (Box 1, Folder 1-11)
  - Hanean, Deelie L. (Box 1, Folder 1-11)
  - Hassell, Jennifer, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 1-11)
  - Heggie, Peter, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 1-11)
  - Held, Marian, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 1-11)
  - Hesse, Helen, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 1-11)
  - Hibbs, Ben, 1948-1949 (Box 1, Folder 1-11)
  - Hills, Robert F., 1948 (Box 1, Folder 1-11)
  - Hughes, Jucy Marshall, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 1-11)
  - Hunt, R. L, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 1-11)
  - Jagels, Adrienne Kelley, 1942-1944 (Box 1, Folder 1-11)
  - Jasper, Helen Jo, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 1-11)
  - Keegan, Martha, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 1-11)
  - Klimetz, Howard, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 1-11)
  - Knight, Ralph, 1949-1951 (Box 1, Folder 1-11)
  - Knopf, Blanche W., 1941 (Box 1, Folder 1-11)
  - Liggett, Clare R., 1947 (Box 1, Folder 1-11)
  - Littauer, Kenneth, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 1-11)
  - Mansfield, Richard, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 1-11)
  - Mochrie, Margaret, 1929-1933 (Box 1, Folder 1-11)
  - Moore, Alfred D., 1935 (Box 1, Folder 1-11)
  - McCall Corporation, 1929-1933 (Box 1, Folder 1-11)
  - McFarland, Wilma K., 1931-1933 (Box 1, Folder 1-11)
  - McIlwain, Virginia, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 1-11)
  - Neall, Adelaide W., 1941 (Box 1, Folder 1-11)
  - O'Connor, Evelyn, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 1-11)
  - Parsons, Betty Brown, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 1-11)
  - Pollack, Merrill, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 1-11)
  - Potts, Bill, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 1-11)
  - Quan, Madeleine W., 1938 (Box 1, Folder 1-11)
  - Rearden, Mary, 1940-1943 (Box 1, Folder 1-11)
  - Raynolds, Paul, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 1-11)
  - Rinehart, Stanley M. Jr., 1940 (Box 1, Folder 1-11)
  - Rose, Stuart, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 1-11)
  - Russell, Mary Ellen, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 1-11)
  - Sammons, Wheeler Jr., 1941 (Box 1, Folder 1-11)
  - Schwab, Frances, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 1-11)
  - Scudder, Jane C., 1946 (Box 1, Folder 1-11)
  - Selby, John, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 1-11)
  - Shea, Frank, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 1-11)
  - Sherer, Adelaide A., 1940 (Box 1, Folder 1-11)
  - Shopkaroff, Michael (Box 1, Folder 1-11)
  - Sironen, Marta, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 1-11)
  - Smith, Carrie D., 1933 (Box 1, Folder 1-11)
  - Stewart, George, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 1-11)
  - Stoddard, Anne, 1933-1943 (Box 1, Folder 1-11)
  - Sughrue, John J., 1946 (Box 1, Folder 1-11)
  - Sunderland, Robert W., 1957 (Box 1, Folder 1-11)
  - Todd, J. Ronald, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 1-11)
  - Tomblin, Pauline M., 1950 (Box 1, Folder 1-11)
  - Tong, Jocelyn, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 1-11)
  - Townsend, Lucille E., 1934 (Box 1, Folder 1-11)
  - Wagstaff, Helen, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 1-11)
  - Wilkinson, Max, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 1-11)
  - Williams, C. N., 1950 (Box 1, Folder 1-11)
  - Williams, Mrs., 1950 (Box 1, Folder 1-11)
  - Word, Mary, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 1-11)
  - Unidentified (Box 1, Folder 1-11)
- Manuscripts (Norma Bicknell)
  - Boss of the Ragged O. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - McAllister Patrol (Box 1, Folder 13-14)
  - Stranger, Ride Away (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - All Very Civilized (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Abolitionist's Trick (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Academic Captive (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Against the Grain (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Andy Larken and the Spirit World (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Another Generation (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Avoid Me Like Danger (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Bargain Bride (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Big Blow (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Big-Hearted Cowboy (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Blind Road (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Born to Ride (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Bottoms Up For Charley (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Build Your Own Dream (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - The Burden of My Freedom (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Buried Gold (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Buy me a Dolly (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Cake at Midnight (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Carve a River (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - The Courtship of Kelly Brown (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Commission Basis (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Coyote Call (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - The Coyote Calls Again (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - A Deal in Futures (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - The Depth of a Fool (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Dollar's Worth of Dust (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Don't Cry On Me (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Don't' Ever Count On Freedom (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Don't Worry About Me. (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - The Editor and the Suffragette (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - The Education of Kelly Brown (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Eat Your Steak, Joe (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Ellen's White Dress (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Elly (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Fan's Daughter (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - The Farmer's Wife (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Fate, and Such (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - The Father of Three Children (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - First Thought For Simon (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - For Myself Alone (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - For the Writer (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Fording Southern Oregon (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Fortieth Birthday (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Four Words (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Free Choice (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Friend or Foe (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - A Gentleman With Man (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - The Ghost at Willow Wells (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Girl For Today (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - The Guarded Heart (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Hat-tit-e-fon-caw's Daughter (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - The Hard Way (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Heritage (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Home-Town Bait (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - The House is Yours (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Housecleaning (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - I Met My Love (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - I Want to Tell You (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - If You Ever Need Me (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - It's Your Life (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Indian Summer (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Iris Out (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Jennie McLoch (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Jig for a Nickel (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Johnny Wingfoot and the Dancing Girl (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Keep Your Dream (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Killer in the Hills (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - King-Size Job (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Kiss Me Again (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Largely Autobiographical (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Let Me Be a Hero (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Live a Little (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Long-Term View (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Look at the Stars (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Lost on Wander Mountain (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Love is a Pitfall (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Love is Forever (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Love is Nonsense (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Love Song (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Ma Prudery and the Upper Set (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Madam So and So (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Make Up Your Mind (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Man Is Meant to Suffer (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - The Man Who Dreamed (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - The Man Who Planned (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - A Man With Principals (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Man's First Duty (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Marry Me, Mary (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - The Meanest Man (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Meet Me on Monday (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - The Menace (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Misery Gulch (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Miss McCarty Meets a Bear (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Money Makes Trouble (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Mortal Enemy (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Mr. Anonymous (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Murder At Red Stove (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Music Man (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - My Father and the Widow Rye (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - My Sweet Angel (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Name, Please (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Never For Me (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Never Story (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - The New Guide (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - No Harm Intended (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - No Medals Attached (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - No Stars (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - No Tears (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - No Unwilling Hand (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Not For Display (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Nothing Good on Greeper Street (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Oh, Bear With Me (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - One Is Forty (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - One Man's Heart (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - One Short Stirrup (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - One Small, Striped, Kitten (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Pat's Secret (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Period Piece (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Please Come Back To Me (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Please Remember (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Plumb Weaponless (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Poor Nellie (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Posted (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - The Professor Asked Instruction (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Promise to Jim (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Rendezvous With Jake (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Ride A White Horse (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - The River That Flows Between (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Run, Sheep, Run (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Rustler's Blaze (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Rustler's Blood (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Shamamam Pass (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Self-Healing Heart (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Seminole Promise (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - She Had a Good Right (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - She Was Live Bait (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - The Sign (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Single-Handed (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Slide Area (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - The Smell of Home (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Some Grow Up Young (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Some People Aren't Honest (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - The Song of Little Davey (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Sullivan Gaines, of Boston (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Take a Lonely Heart (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Take the Day (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Take Me Home Again (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Tangled Web (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Tell That to the Iing (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - The Tiger Returns (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - There Was Some Trouble (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - This Is A Love Song (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - This Is My Son (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - This Precious Thing (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - A Time of Change (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Timothy and the Widow Pinkerton (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - To Be A Man (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - To Melody (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Too Many Rules (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Two Good Soldiers (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Type Q, Queer (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - The Unguarded Heart (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Unto the Hills (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Voice of the Redbird (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Wait for Tomorrow (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Walkaway (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - A War-Bonnet for Dirty Paw (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - We Will Be Called (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - We'll All Help You (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Whipping Boy (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - White Girl Much Good (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Who Am I? (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Who Rides Alone? (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Who's a Thief? (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Who's On First? (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Will You Wait For Me? (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Wrong For Each Other (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Wu (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Yesterday Was Dying (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - You'll Like It (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Young Parson (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Younger Brother (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Gambler's Daughter or Dangerous Man (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - After Five Years (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Big Farmer (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Untitled (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Loose Pages (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Briefs, Sketches, Outlines and Ideas for Stories (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Notes, Research and Background Material (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Manuscripts rewritten by Norma B. Mansfield (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Publications (Norma Bicknell)
  - "All Very Civilized" Macleans, 1938 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "Bargain Bride" Saturday Evening Post, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "The Betrayal" The American Magazine, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "Buried Gold" Torchbearer, 1932 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "Change of Tune" Colliers, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "Control" The American Girl, 1942 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "The Cowboy Who Wouldn't Fall" Saturday Evening Post, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "Coyote Call" Torchbearer, 1932 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "The Coyote Calls Again" Torchbearer, 1932 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "The Date For the Wedding" Saturday Evening Post, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "The Daughter of Hat-tit-t-fon-caw" The American Girl, 1930 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "Don't Worry About Me" Liberty, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "Easier Than Working" Saturday Evening Post, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "The Education of Kelly Brown" Saturday Evening Post, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "Ellen's White Dress" Torchbearer, 1930 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "Everybody's Two People" Chatelaine, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "Fan's Daughter" Colliers, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "The Farmer's Wife" The All Story Braille Magazine, 1942 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "A Father's Gift" Cosmopolitan, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "Forever With Me" McCall's, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "Four Words" Colliers, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "Free Choice" Colliers, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "Friend or Foe" Torchbearer, 1932 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "Get the Rig Through" Saturday Evening Post, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "The Hard Way", 1940 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "Hidden Heart" The American Magazine, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "The Hold-Up Bears" The Epworth Highroad, 1929 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "In Joy Andin Sorrow" Colliers, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "Jig for a Nickel" Woman's Day, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "Keeper of the Wolves" The American Girl (Part II-V), 1934 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "King Joins the Army" The American Girl, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "King-Size Job" The American Girl, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "Late in Love" Saturday Evening Post, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "Love Happens" Colliers, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "Love Is an Art" Woman, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "Love, Love, Go Away" McCall's, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "Make-Believe Dog" The American Girl (Part I-VI), 1938 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "The Marriage Market" Saturday Evening Post, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "The Menace" The American Girl (Part I-II), 1934 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "Misery Gulch" Torchbearer, 1932 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "Miss McCarthy Mets a Bear" The Epworth Highroad, 1932 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "Moment of Emotion" Saturday Evening Post, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "The New Guide" Torchbearer, 1932 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "No Room For Love" Saturday Evening Press, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "No Tears" The American Magazine, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "Notes on Writing For the Slicks" The Writer, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "The Orneriest Man in Town" Saturday Evening Post, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "Pat's Secret" Torchbearer, 1932 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "Plumb Weaponless" Torchbearer, 1932 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "Pooch" Portal, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "Prove You Love Me" Saturday Evening Post, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "Rancho Del Sur" Torchbearer (Chapter 1-8), 1935 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "Samamam Pass" The Epworth Highroad, 1933 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "Sailor's Return" Saturday Evening Post, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "Seminole Promise" Torchbearer, 1930 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "The Sign" Torchbearer, 1932 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "Some Grow Up Young" Saturday Evening Post, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "Something to Build On" Colliers, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "Stay Out of My Life" McCall's, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "Stuff of Heroes" Colliers, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "Sullivan Gaines" Maclean's, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "There Goes My Man" Every Woman, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "There's Always One" McCall's, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "This Is My Son" Liberty, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "This Precious Thing" McCall's, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "The Tiger Returns" Torchbearer, 1932 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "Timothy and the Widow Pinkerton" Chatelaine, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "To Be A Man" The Haversack, 1929 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "Too Many Rules" The Epworth High Road, 1933 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "Too Smart to Marry" Saturday Evening Post, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "Too Wise For Love" Chatelaine, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "Walk-Away" Torchbearer, 1929 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "Where Were You Last Night?" McCall's, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "Where's That Man I Married?" Chatelaine, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "White Girl Much Good?" Torchbearer, 1929 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "Wife Auction" Saturday Evening Post, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "Wild Streak" Liberty, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "Will You Wait For Me?" Colliers, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "Wu" Torchbearer, 1929 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "Yesterday Was Dying" Colliers, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "You'll Like It" Etc., 1940 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Correspondence (Robert Mansfield)
  - Brandt, Carl, 1936-1948 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Brandt Brandt, 1936-1948 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Chamburn, Jacques, 1937 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Chappell, Edwin B. Jr., 1926-1930 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Dany, Louise, 1939 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Donaldson, B. R., 1926 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Ferguson, Rowena, 1931 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Guthrie, E. R., 1951 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Hughes, Lucy M., 1929-1930 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Hunt, R. L., 1930-1935 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Littauer, Kenneth, 1938 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Moore, Alfred D., 1929-1930 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Morris, A. R., 1924 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Neuberger, Richard, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - O'Connor, Evelyn, 1928 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Gursler, Fullton, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Pancner, F., 1933 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Pierrot, George, 1929 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Porter, Eugenia, 1927 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Simpson, Oscar, 1928-1929 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Stewart, George, 1929-1930 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Taylor, Evelyn B., 1939 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - The Tylers, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Vilimek, Joseph R., 1933 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - West, James E., 1928 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - White, Stewart, Edward, 1931 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Unidentified, 1952 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Manuscripts (Robert Mansfield)
  - Eyes of Congo (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - The Lost Leader (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Untitled (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Bequest (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Fool's Mate (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Going Home (Box 5, Folder 6)